Guide to the Grace Cavalieri papers, 1945-2022 MS2007
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
- DVDs, 2005-2016; Series 8
  - On the Go AAUW Poetry reading Mary Wollstonecraft [2/2], 2005 (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - On the Go AAUW Poets are Entrepreneurs, undated (Box 66, Folder 21)
    Grace Cavalieri hosts; WDC Poets Karen Alenier, Sarah Browning
  - Jeanne Mozier: On the Go with AAUW, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 1)
  - The Poet and the Poem, 2012; Series 8 (Box 104, Folder 4)
  - The Poet and the Poem, 2013; Series 8 (Box 106, Folder 3)
    2 DVDS with interviews with Shara McCallum and Sharon Dolan
  - Poet William Meredith, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 2)
  - Eavan Boland Interview, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 3)
  - WDC Guests: On the Go with AAUW, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 4)
  - WDC Guests: Ont he Go with AAUW, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 5)
  - Kim Roberts and Teri Cross: On the Go with AAUW, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 6)
  - Grace Cavalieri and Ariden Shashaani: On the Go with AAUW, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 7)
  - Grace Cavalieri and Sabine Pascarelli teaching/translation poetry reading, 11/23/2009; Series 8 (Box 96, Dvd 1)
  - Barbara Goldberg and Maria Van Beuren: On the Go with AAUW, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 8)
  - Patricia Gray: On the Go with AAUW, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 9)
  - Ann Bracken: On the Go with AAUW, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 10)
  - Reed Whitemore TV Show, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 11)
  - WPFW 30th Anniversary, undated; Series 8 (Box 91, Dvd 12)
  - Author and Activist: The Daniela Gioseffi Story, 2016; Series 8 (Box 114, Folder 8)
- Digital Audio Tapes, 1992-1997; Series 9
  This series contains Digital Audio Tape recordings, consisting primarily of Grace Cavalieri's collaborative work with composer Vivian Adelberg Rudow; there are also several unidentified DATs. Recordings of collaborative work include "Migrations," "The Healing Place," and "I Pledge My Love."
  - Hazrat Pir, 04/20/1995 (Box 66, Folder 22)
  - The Healing Place VI no words, undated (Box 66, Folder 23)
  - The Healing Place VI acoustic and electronic copy, 03/06/1993 (Box 66, Folder 24)
  - The Healing Place with narration, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 25)
  - I Pledge My Love, undated (Box 66, Folder 26)
    music by Vivian Adelberg Rudow and lyrics by Grace Cavalieri
  - Kirk Judd, undated (Box 66, Folder 27)
  - John Mc, undated (Box 66, Folder 28)
  - Irene McKinney, undated (Box 66, Folder 29)
  - Migrations radio stops at Bendit distertion, undated (Box 66, Folder 30)
  - Migrations, undated (Box 66, Folder 31)
    Box 47 Folder 16 contains two CD recordings of Migrations.
  - Migrations, undated (Box 66, Folder 32)
    music and spoken words for Guide music; music by Vivian Adelberg Rudow and poetry by Cavalieri. Box 47 Folder 16 contains two CD recordings of Migrations.
  - Migrations radio copy, 01/31/1997 (Box 66, Folder 33)
    sound edited from reel to reel. Box 47 Folder 16 contains two CD recordings of Migrations.
  - Migrations music, 07/29/1992 (Box 66, Folder 34)
    copyright Vivian Adelberg Rudow. Box 47 Folder 16 contains two CD recordings of Migrations.
  - "The Poet and the Poem, WPFW: Rap Special.", Series 9 (Box 100, Folder 8)
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    DAT (Digital Audio Tape) format.
  - unidentified, undated (Box 66, Folder 35)
- Correspondence, 1963-2019; Series 10
  Arranged chronologically.
  This series contains correspondence produced and received by Grace Cavalieri. The bulk of the correspondence dates from 1970 to 2015, and includes typed and handwritten letters, postcards, and e-mail. The material is arranged into three groups based upon Cavalieri's original order. The first group, "Correspondence - Louis Catron" consists of correspondence between Grace Cavalieri and playwright Louis Catron during 1970. The second group, "Correspondence - General" includes correspondence from 1963 to 2019 not subsumed by another series in the collection or categorized by Cavalieri. The third group, "Correspondence - Submissions," consists of acceptance and rejection letters from publishers and producers.
  - Louis Catron, 1970 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Submissions, 1972-1973 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Submissions, 1988-1997 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Submissions, 1994-1999 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Submissions, 1999-2000 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Submissions, 2000-2002 (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Submissions, 2004-2006 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Submissions, 01/10/2003 --03/16/2006 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Acceptance and Rejection Slips, Notes of Poetry and Plays [1/2], 2007-2015; Series 10 (Box 114, Folder 9)
  - Acceptance and Rejection Slips, Notes of Poetry and Plays [2/2], 2007-2015; Series 10 (Box 114, Folder 10)
  - Note about Reed Whittmore, 1982; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - George Billings letter, 11/1982; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - Jim McCartin letter, 1986; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Sterling Stuckey letter, 10/1990; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Poets May Inqiury, 06/2003; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Reccomendation for Poet Laureate, 12/2003; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Joan Picard letter, 06/2004; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - General correspondence, 1963-1978 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 12/1979; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 1)
    Note in "The Illuminated Language of Flowers"
  - General correspondence, 1980-2005 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 2006; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - General correspondence, 2006-2007 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 01/01/2007-10/01/2007; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence, 10/01/2007-D12/31/2007; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence, 01/01/2008- 04/24/2008; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 12)
  - General Correspondence, 04/24/2008-11/12/2008; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 13)
  - General Correspondence, 12/12/2008- 12/31/2008; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 14)
  - General correspondence, 2005-2009; Series 10 (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - General correspondence, 2009; Series 10 (Box 96, Folder 2)
    original title supplied by donor was "letters and docs"
  - General correspondence /PR, 2010; Series 10 (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, undated; Series 10 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 1945-2011; 2010-2011; Series 10 (Box 98, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence, 2004-2010; Series 10 (Box 98, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence, 2001-2011; Series 10 (Box 99, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 2013 May; Series 10 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Dan Vera e-mail, 08/2008; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 15)
  - Here Even the Blue Crabs Compose, 2009; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 16)
  - Harper Collins Publisher letter, 03/2009; Series 10 (Box 92, Folder 17)
  - General Correspondence, 01/01/2009- 05/21/2009; Series 10 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Submissions, undated; Series 10 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - "Salt Lick" Correspondence, undated; Series 10 (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Mary Bonutio Letter, 06/1974; Series 10 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2010; Series 10 (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 2011-2012; Series 10 (Box 100, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2012; Series 10 (Box 104, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2012; Series 10 (Box 104, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2012; Series 10 (Box 104, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2012; Series 10 (Box 104, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2012; Series 10 (Box 104, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2013 May; Series 8 (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence about death of husband, Kenneth, 2013 January-March; Series 10 (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - General Correspondence, 2013 Spring; Series 10 (Box 106, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2013; Series 10 (Box 110, Folder 3)
    Various correspondences, including an email with Robert Pinsky.
  - Correspondence, 2013; Series 10 (Box 110, Folder 4)
    Various correspondences, including the reward letter for the Ginsberg Poetry Award.
  - Correspondence, 2013; Series 10 (Box 110, Folder 5)
    Various correspondence.
  - Correspondence, 2013-2014; Series 10 (Box 110, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2013-2014; Series 10 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    Various correspondence
  - Correspondence, Circa 2013-2015; Series 10 (Box 115, Folder 1)
  - Letters, 2014 June 6-2015 March 15; Series 10 (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2014; Series 10 (Box 110, Folder 7)
    Various correspondences.
  - Correspondence, July 2014-February 2015; Series 10 (Box 111, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1979-2015; Series 10 (Box 112, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2015 April; Series 10 (Box 112, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 2015-2016; Series 10 (Box 115, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 2016; Series 10 (Box 115, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 2016 February-April; Series 10 (Box 115, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 2016 April-June; Series 10 (Box 115, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2016 May-December; Series 10 (Box 115, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2017-2019; Series 10 (Box 116, Folder 13)
- Collaborative Work, 1956-2014; Series 11
  This series consists of material related to Grace Cavalieri's collaborative work with psychic Bryan Christopher, with musician and composer Vivian Adelberg Rudow, and with visual artist Mary Ellen Long. The series is divided into three sections according to collaborator: "Christopher," "Long," and "Rudow." Materials in the "Christopher" section are undated, and include a photograph of Christopher and a draft of the introductory chapter to the collaborative work "Light Energy." The bulk of the "Long" section dates from 1965 to 2014, and includes correspondence, drafts, galleys and proofs, slides and photographs, biographical information about Mary Ellen Long, promotional materials, and original artwork by Long. The artwork includes over-sized, signed and numbered prints, and a large, framed piece of art related to the work "Migrations." The bulk of the "Rudow" section dates from 1980 to 1998, and includes correspondence, drafts, musical scores and music manuscript, programs, scripts, clippings and reviews, and biographical information about Rudow.
  - Bryan Christopher, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Mary Ellen Long, 1992-2007 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Mary Ellen Long, art [1/2], 1984 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Mary Ellen Long, art [2/2], 1990 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Mary Ellen Long - biographical Information, 1991 (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Mary Ellen Long- Correspondence [1/2], 1965-2003; Series 11 (Box 115, Folder 7)
  - Mary Ellen Long- Correspondence [2/2], 1965-2003; Series 11 (Box 115, Folder 8)
  - Mary Ellen Long - correspondence [1/12], 1966-2003 (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Mary Ellen Long - correspondence [2/12], 1968 (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Mary Ellen Long - correspondence [3/12], 1965-1966 (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Mary Ellen Long - correspondence [4/12], 1967-1968 (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Mary Ellen Long - correspondence [5/12], 1968 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Mary Ellen Long - correspondence [6/12], 1969 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Mary Ellen Long - correspondence [7/12], 1970-1974 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Mary Ellen Long - correspondence [8/12], 1975-1979 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Mary Ellen Long- correspondence [9/12], 1981-1989 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Mary Ellen Long - correspondence [10/12], 1990-1992 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Mary Ellen Long- correspondence [11/12], 1994-1999 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Mary Ellen Long - correspondence [12/12], 2003-2007 (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Creature Comforts, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Ellie the Elephant, 1956-2003 (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Exhibitions and installations, 1989-2007 (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Mary Ellen Long-Journey of an Artist, 2014; Series 11 (Box 112, Folder 11)
  - Mary Ellen Long- letters and brochures, undated (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Little Line, 2003-2006 (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Little Line, galley, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Migrations, 1995-1996 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Migrations - galley, undated (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Migrations - photographs, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Migrations - slides, undated (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Pinecrest Rest Haven, 1996-2001 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Poetry, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Prints, 1968-1970 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Mary Ellen Long - slides, 1966-1975 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Sticks and Stars for Supper, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Sticks and Stars for Dinner - galley, undated (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Today I Was Alone, 2002 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Today Without My Friend, undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Mary Ellen Long- various, undated (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Mary Ellen Long- various, undated (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow, 1983-1989 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    Includes one photograph
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - biographical information, undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Blue Bird, 1985 (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - correspondence, 1981-2004 (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Day's Song, 01/26/1985 (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Epothalamions, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Healing Place, 1985 (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Hello Friends; Welcome, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Get With Me, Baby/ Ya Gotta Know Me, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - I Pledge My Love, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - I will Not Be There, 01/16/1987 (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - I Will Over Come; Oh Yes I Will, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Journey of Waters - performance, 04/26/2006 (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Journey of Waters - scores, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Let's Be Friends, 1988 (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Libretti, 1984-1987 (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Libretti, 1984-1987 (Box 47, Folder 13)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Light Waters, 05/21/1984 (Box 47, Folder 14)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Liquid Gold, 1987 (Box 47, Folder 15)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Migrations, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 16)
    This folder contains photographs, paper records, two CDs and the chapbook Migrations.
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Moonlight and Roses, 1992 (Box 47, Folder 17)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Portrait of a Friend, 1986-1992 (Box 47, Folder 18)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Purple Ice, 1992 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Res Musica, 1986-1988 (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Running, undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - scores -unidentified, undated (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Seasons of Woman, undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Shadows in the Wind, 1985 (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Song of Courage, 08/01/1987 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - String of Pearls, 1984-1987 (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - String of Pearls - scores, 1984-1989 (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - String of Pearls - scores [1/2], 1984-1989 (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - String of Pearls - scores [2/2], 1984-1989 (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Take My Hand, 1983 (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Mary Ellen Long - art, undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Little Line, undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Devy's Song, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - The Healing Place, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Journey of Waters, 1984 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - A Love Song for Billy, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Portrait of a Friend, 1985-1986 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Requiem Mass for Devy, undated (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow "Sound Portraits", 2013; Series 11 (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - String of the Pearls [1/3], 1984-1989 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - String of the Pearls [2/3], 1987 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - String of the Pearls [3/3], undated (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - White Ribbons of Love, 1985 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Mary Ellen Long - Prints, 1968-1970 (Box 57, Folder 4)
    Oversize items
  - Mary Ellen Long - prints, 1971-1972 (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Mary Ellen Long - prints, undated (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Mary Ellen Long - prints, undated (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Get With Me Baby/ Ya Gotta Know Me, 1989 (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Journey of Waters, 1984 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Portrait of a Friend, 1986 (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Vivian Adelberg Rudow - Variations, undated (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Silk Screens Mary Ellen Long and Grace Cavalieri, 1969-1970 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - The gold whistled back wind, 1969 (Box 67, Item 1.1)
  - Eavesdropping miracles, 1969 (Box 67, Item 1.2)
  - Pure as pain, 1970 (Box 67, Item 1.3)
  - The sounds of us, 1970 (Box 67, Item 1.4)
  - Listen to its sobbing (hold my wrist), 1970 (Box 67, Item 1.5)
  - Silk Screens Mary Ellen Long and Grace Cavalieri, 1971 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - In Man, 1971 (Box 67, Item 2.1)
  - The Inhalation of the Dream and Being IV, 1971 (Box 67, Item 2.2)
  - The Inhalation of the Dream and Being III, 1971 (Box 67, Item 2.3)
  - The Inhalation of the Dream and Being II, 1971 (Box 67, Item 2.4)
  - The Inhalation of the Dream and Being I, 1971 (Box 67, Item 2.5)
  - Silk Screens Mary Ellen Long and Grace Cavalieri, 1972 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - Whelming, 1972 (Box 67, Item 3.1)
  - Returning, 1972 (Box 67, Item 3.2)
  - Promise, 1972 (Box 67, Item 3.3)
  - Entering, 1972 (Box 67, Item 3.4)
  - Under, 1972 (Box 67, Item 3.5)
  - Silk Screens Mary Ellen Long and Grace Cavalieri, 1974 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Invasion, 1972 (Box 67, Item 4.1)
  - Cradling the light, 1974 (Box 67, Item 4.2)
  - Skin softens, 1974 (Box 67, Item 4.3)
  - ... from the leaf to sky, my love, 1974 (Box 67, Item 4.4)
  - Where you be curled, 1975 (Box 67, Item 4.5)
  - Silk Screens Mary Ellen Long and Grace Cavalieri, 1975 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Floating like light, 1975 (Box 67, Item 5.1)
  - cooling from our edges in, 1975 (Box 67, Item 5.2)
  - with petals, 1975 (Box 67, Item 5.3)
  - fragrant of surfaces floating, 1975 (Box 67, Item 5.4)
  - climbing into ourselves, we lay, 1975 (Box 67, Item 5.5)
  - Pyramid thoughts, undated (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Cutting the moon, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Bail the water, 1971 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - "No War", undated (Box 69, Folder 1)
    inscribed "Grace, Thanks for your lessons. You changed my life Love, Mark"
  - Climax, 1972 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Leaping Distance, 1966 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - Notice, 1972 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Bring, 1971 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - ... afloat, 1974 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - The way well the way a poet begins, undated (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - the love between, 1968 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Departing gethsemane, 1969 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - baby doll images from book Migrations, undated (Box 85, Item 1)
    This framed item is the work of artist Cindy Cavalieri. The photographs are from Grace Cavalieri's book Migrations and the photographs taken by Mary Ellen Long.
- Poet and the Poem Radio Show Supporting Materials, 1976-2015; Series 12
  This series is composed of administrative material related to Cavalieri's radio program, "The Poet and the Poem." Materials include awards, correspondence, notes and project proposals, program announcements and publicity, biographical information about poets interviewed, financial information, and transcripts. Material related to the program's national distribution through The Library of Congress, National Public Radio, Pacifica Radio, and Rhino is also included. The series also contains material pertaining to WPFW-FM, the radio station that broadcast "The Poet and the Poem" from 1977 to 1997.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - Poet and the Poem - Awards, 1985-1998 (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Poet and the Poem - 34th Anniversary Program, 2011 November; Series 12 (Box 98, Folder 6)
  - Poet and the Poem - Brown, Sterling A., 1989 (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Poet and the Poem - correspondence, 05/09/1984 --05/24/2007 (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Poet and the Poem - distribution, 1987-2003 (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Poet and the Poem - distribution - National Public Radio, 1990-2006 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Poet and the Poem - distribution - Pacifica Radio, 1980-2004 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Poet and the Poem - distribution - Rhino, 1999-2004 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Poet and the Poem - Excellence in Print Award, 2000-2005 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Poet and the Poem - Finances, 1977-2003 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Poet and the Poem - Frasca, Timothy, 2005 (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Poet and the Poem - General, 1980-2007 (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Poet and the Poem - Library of Congress - Poetry Collection Assessment- Libbie Rifkin, undated (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Poet and the Poem - Library of Congress - Poet Laureates [1/2], 2005-2007 (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Poet and the Poem- Library of Congress - Poet Laureates [2/2], 1999-2005 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Poet and the Poem- Meredith, William, 2007 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Poet and the Poem- Poets' Curriculum Vitae and biographies, 1975-2002 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Poet and the Poem- program announcements and subscriptions, 1986-2003 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Poet and the Poem- project proposals, 1994-2000 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Poet and the Poem- publicity [2/2], 1987-2006 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Poet and the Poem- publicity [1/2], 1987-2007 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Poet and the Poem - Transcriptions, 1995-2003 (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Poet and the Poem - West Virginia Special, 1996 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Poet and the Poem - Witter Bynner Foundation of Poetry, 1998-2003 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Poet and the Poem - WPFW [1/2], 1976-2002 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Poet and the Poem - WPFW [2/2], 1976-2002 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Poet and the Poem - WPFW Jazz Benefit, 1987 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Poet and the Poem - List of Programs at Pacifica Program Service, 2011; Series 12 (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Transcripts of U.S Poet Laureates [1/2], 1988-2015; Series 12 (Box 115, Folder 9)
  - Transcripts of U.S Poet Laureates [2/2], 1988-2015; Series 12 (Box 115, Folder 10)
- Employment, 1955-2007; Series 13
  This series contains materials that document Cavalieri's professional employment beyond her entrepreneurial endeavors and radio programs. The series is divided into three sections: "Public Broadcasting System (PBS)," "Teaching," and "Washington Writers' Publishing House." The bulk of the PBS section dates to 1979, and includes administrative material such as reports, budgets, correspondence, and memoranda related to Cavalieri's position as Associate Director of Programming for PBS. The second section, "Teaching" includes documents pertaining to Cavalieri's years as an elementary school teacher, as a professor and visiting playwright at Antioch College in Ohio during the 1960s and early 1970s, as a visiting poet at St. Mary's College in Maryland, and as a leader of writing workshops and retreats. The third section includes material relevant to Cavalieri's administrative and editorial work for the Washington Writers' Publishing House.
  - Public Broadcasting Service, 1979 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Teaching - Antioch College, 1968 (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Teaching - Antioch College - student work, 1973 (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Teaching - Howard County Poetry and Literature Society, 2002 (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Teaching - International Society of Poets, 2002-2005 (Box 52, Folder 4)